Guide to the Bayrd Still Papers MC.44
New York University Archives
- Series III: NYC Research, 1650-1989
  - Subseries C: Sources about Urbanism and Urban Development
    - Hart, Albert B., "The Rise of American Cities," QUARTERLY JOURNAL OF ECONOMICS, IV (January, 1890), undated (Box 35, Folder 1)
      3 1142 04225075 6
    - Growth of Cities in West, Denver, 1890, undated (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Godkin, E. L., Immigrants in Municipal Politics, 1890, undated (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - White, Andrew, "The Government of American Cities, FORUM, X (December, 1890), undated (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Pingree, Hazen, Veto of Street Railway Franchise, July 2, 1891, undated (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Abbott, Lyman, Reference to "Great Cities," 1891, undated (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Howard, W. W., "The City of Milwaukee," HARPER'S WEEKLY MAGAZINE, XXXV (July 18, 1891), undated (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Depopulation of rural districts, NATION, LII, April 23, 1891, undated (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Hull House; Chicago Commons, 1892, 1904, Jane Addams, Robert A. Woods, undated (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - The Poor in Great Cities, Series began in SCRIBNER'S MAGAZINE, XI, April 1892, undated (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - National Municipal League, 1894, ff., undated (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - Booth, Maud Ballington, "Salvation Army Work in the Slums," 1895, undated (Box 35, Folder 12)
    - Howells, Wm. D., IMPRESSIONS AND EXPERIENCES, East-Side Tenements, Central Park, New York Streets, 1895, undated (Box 35, Folder 13)
    - Kingsbury, F. J., "The Tendency of Men to Live in Cities," JOURNAL OF SOCIAL SCIENCE, XXVIII, 1895, undated (Box 35, Folder 14)
    - Roosevelt, Theo., "The City in American Life," Review of Albert Shaw, MUNICIPAL GOVERNMENT IN GREAT BRITAIN, ATLANTIC MONTHLY, LXXV, January - June 1895, undated (Box 35, Folder 15)
    - Fletcher, Henry, "The Drift of Drift of Population to Cities: Remedies," FORUM, XIX, August 1895, undated (Box 35, Folder 16)
    - Means, D. M., "The Growth of Cities," NATION, Aug. 8, 1895, undated (Box 35, Folder 17)
    - Roosevelt, Theo., "The Higher Life of American Cities," THE OUTLOOK, Dec. 22, 1895, undated (Box 35, Folder 18)
    - Lexow Investigation, 1895, undated (Box 35, Folder 19)
    - Shaw, Albert, "The Higher Life of New York City," THE OUTLOOK, Jan. 26, 1896, undated (Box 35, Folder 20)
    - Goodnow, Frank J., MUNICIPAL PROBLEMS; Preface dated February, 1897, undated (Box 35, Folder 21)
    - Quincy, Josiah, "The Development of American Cities," THE ARENA, XVII, March 1897, undated (Box 35, Folder 22)
    - True, Dr. A. C., "The Solidarity of Town and Farm," THE ARENA, XVII, March 1897, undated (Box 35, Folder 23)
    - Commons, John R., "The Coming City," OUR COUNTRY, V, April 1897, undated (Box 35, Folder 24)
    - Strong, Josiah, "The Problem of the Twentieth Century City," NORTH AMERICAN REVIEW, CLXV, September 1897, undated (Box 35, Folder 25)
    - Godkin, E. L., "Peculiarities of American Municipal Government," ATLANTIC MONTHLY, LXXX, November 1897, undated (Box 35, Folder 26)
    - Pingree, Hazen, Address, Nineteenth Century Club (New York), Nov. 11, 1897, undated (Box 35, Folder 27)
    - Olson, Frederick I., Milwaukee Socialist Party, 1897-1912, 1947 (Box 35, Folder 28)
    - Conine, Martha A. B., "Women's Work in Denver," MUNICIPAL AFFAIRS, II, September 1898, undated (Box 35, Folder 29)
    - Weber, Adna F., "Suburban Annexations," NORTH AMERICAN REVIEW, CLXVI, May 1898, undated (Box 35, Folder 30)
    - Woods, Robert A., ed., THE CITY WILDERNESS, 1898, undated (Box 35, Folder 31)
    - Strong, Josiah, THE TWENTIETH-CENTURY CITY, 1898, undated (Box 35, Folder 32)
    - James, Edmund J., "The Growth of Great Cities in Area and Population," ANNALS OF THE AMERICAN ACADEMY OF POLITICAL AND SOCIAL SCIENCE, XIII, 1899, undated (Box 35, Folder 33)
    - Dewey, John, Education and Urbanization, 1899, undated (Box 35, Folder 34)
    - National Municipal League, A MUNICIPAL PROGRAM, Review in MUNICIPAL AFFAIRS, IV, March 1900, undated (Box 35, Folder 35)
    - Cutting, R. Fulton, "Public Ownership and the Social Conscience," MUNICIPAL AFFAIRS, March 1900, undated (Box 35, Folder 36)
    - Rowe, Leo S., "The City in History," AMERICAN JOURNAL OF SOCIOLOGY, V, May 1900, undated (Box 35, Folder 37)
    - Municipal Progressivism, ca. 1900, undated (Box 35, Folder 38)
    - New Impulse to Suburbanism Revealed in Census of 1900, undated (Box 35, Folder 39)
    - Klaghorn, Kate H., "The Changing Character of Immigration," WORLD'S WORK, I, 1900-1901, undated (Box 35, Folder 40)
    - Milwaukee City Promotion, 1901, undated (Box 35, Folder 41)
    - Brace, Charles L., Cities and Children of Poor, 1901, undated (Box 35, Folder 42)
    - Weber, Adna F., "Growth of Cities in U.S., 1890-1900," MUNICIPAL AFFAIRS, V, 1901, undated (Box 35, Folder 43)
    - Weber, Adna F., "Rapid Transit and the Housing Problem," MUNICIPAL AFFAIRS, VI, 1902, undated (Box 35, Folder 44)
    - Woods, Robert A., AMERICANS IN PROCESS: A SETTLEMENT STUDY, 1902, undated (Box 35, Folder 45)
    - Steiner, Edward A., "Russian and Polish Jews in New York," THE OUTLOOK, LXXII, 1902, undated (Box 35, Folder 46)
    - Ely, Richard T., THE COMING CITY, 1902, undated (Box 35, Folder 47)
    - Bridgman, Howard A., "The Suburbanite," THE INDEPENDENT, LIV, 1902, undated (Box 35, Folder 48)
    - Zueblin, Charles, Writings, 1902 through 1915, undated (Box 35, Folder 49)
    - Woodruff, Clinton R., "The Nationalization of Municipal Movements," ANNALS OF THE AMERICAN ACADEMY OF POLITICAL AND SOCIAL SCIENCE, XXI, March 1903, undated (Box 35, Folder 50)
    - Davenport, Wm. E., "The Italian Immigrant in America," THE OUTLOOK, LXXIII, 1903, undated (Box 35, Folder 51)
    - Fawcett, Waldon, "Suburban Life in America," COSMOPOLITAN, XXXV, 1903, undated (Box 35, Folder 52)
    - Lubin, Z. [Israel Hurwitz], Interpretation of New York City's East Side, 1903, undated (Box 35, Folder 53)
    - Hapgood, Hutchins, Review by Grace I. Colbran of his SPIRIT OF THE GHETTO, BOOKMAN, XVII, 1903, undated (Box 35, Folder 54)
    - Taylor, Graham, "Function of the City Church, " CHAUTAUQUAN, XXXVIII, 1903, undated (Box 35, Folder 55)
    - Jones, Samuel M. (Golden Rule), Recollections of John B. Merrell, concerning, THE COMMONS, IX, 1904, undated (Box 35, Folder 56)
    - Wilcox, Delos F., THE AMERICAN CITY: A PROBLEM IN DEMOCRACY, 1904, undated (Box 35, Folder 57)
    - Weber, Adna, "The Significance of Recent City Growth: the Era of Small Industrial Centres," ANNALS OF THE AMERICAN ACADEMY OF POLITICAL AND SOCIAL SCIENCE, XXIII, 1904, undated (Box 35, Folder 58)
    - Subway, Opening of New York, 1904, undated (Box 35, Folder 59)
    - Norton, Eliot, "The Need of a General Plan for Settling Immigrants outside the Great Cities," CHARITIES, XII, 1904, undated (Box 35, Folder 60)
    - Commons, John R., "City Life, Crime, and Poverty," CHAUTAUQUAN, XXXIX, 1904, undated (Box 35, Folder 61)
    - Woods, Robert A., "Notes on the Italians in Boston," CHARITIES, XIII (1904), undated (Box 35, Folder 62)
    - Mangano, Antonio, "The Associated Life of the Italians in New York," CHARITIES, XII (1904), 1904 May 7 (Box 36, Folder 1)
      3 1142 04225074 9
    - Goodnow, Frank J., CITY GOVERNMENT IN THE UNITED STATES, 1910; Preface dated 1904, 1904, 1910 (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Howe, Frederic C., THE CITY: THE HOPE OF DEMOCRACY; Preface dated Sep. 1, 1905, 1905 Sept 1-1906 (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Carlton, Frank T., "Urban and Rural Life," POPULAR SCIENCE MONTHLY, LXVIII (1906), 1906 Jan.- 1906 June (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Davis, Michael M., "Civic Interest Among the People," CHARITIES AND THE COMMONS, XVII (1906), 1906 Oct. - 1907 Apr. (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - James, William, Letter describing New York City in 1907, in Henry James, ed., THE LETTERS OF WILLIAM JAMES (1920), II, 263-65 (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - "Suburban Cottages vs. Flats," THE INDEPENDENT, LXII (1907) (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - Riis, Jacob, "What Settlements Stand For," THE OUTLOOK, LXXXIX -1908 (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Marsh, Benjamin C., "City Planning in Justice to the Working Population," CHARITIES AND THE COMMONS, XX (1908), 1908 Feb. 1 (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - Speranza, Gino C., "The Italians in Congested Districts," CHARITIES AND THE COMMONS, XX (1908) (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - Kinley, David, "The Movement of Population from Country to City, in L. H. Bailey, CYCLOPEDIA OF AMERICAN AGRICULTURE, (1909), 116-17 (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - Robinson, Charles M., "A Civic Revival," THE SURVEY, XXII (1909), 1909 August 14 (Box 36, Folder 12)
    - Grant, Arthur H., "The Coming of Age of Our Cities," THE AMERICAN CITY, I (1909), 1909 Sept. (Box 36, Folder 13)
    - Nolen, John, "City Making," THE AMERICAN CITY, I (1909), 1909 Sept. (Box 36, Folder 14)
    - Burton, Theodore E., "Civic Betterment," THE AMERICAN CITY, I -1909, 1909 Sept. (Box 36, Folder 15)
    - Hooker, George E., "A Plan for Chicago," THE SURVEY, XXII (1909), 1909 Sept. 4 (Box 36, Folder 16)
    - Fitch, Clyde, "The City," a play originally produced Dec. 22, 1909, 1909 Dec. 22 (Box 36, Folder 17)
    - Wilcox, Delos F., GREAT CITIES IN AMERICA: THEIR PROBLEMS AND THEIR GOVERNMENT; Preface dated 1910 (Box 36, Folder 18)
    - Census of 1910, Data on Suburbs (Box 36, Folder 19)
    - Remarks on the City Club and the City Beautiful, CITY CLUB OF PHILADELPHIA BULLETIN, 1910 (Box 36, Folder 20)
    - Ritchie, Ryerson, Commercial Organizations and Planning, CITY CLUB OF PHILADELPHIA BULLETIN, 1910 (Box 36, Folder 21)
    - Weirick, Ray F., "The Park and Boulevard System of Kansas City," THE AMERICAN CITY, III (1910), 1910 Jul. - 1910 Dec. (Box 36, Folder 22)
    - Almy, Frederic, "The Huddled Poles of Buffalo," THE SURVEY, XXV (1911) (Box 36, Folder 23)
    - Roosevelt, Theodore, "A Visit to the Tenements," in "The American Worker in Country and Town," THE OUTLOOK, XCVII (1911) (Box 36, Folder 24)
    - Beard, Charles A., "Recent Activities of City Clubs," NATIONAL MUNICIPAL REVIEW, I (1912) (Box 36, Folder 25)
    - Ford, Geo. B., "Digging Deeper Deeper into City Planning" and reaction thereto by Charles M. Robinson and Benjamin C. Marsh, THE AMERICAN CITY (March, 1912), 1912 March (Box 36, Folder 26)
    - Howe, Frederic C., "In Defense of the American City," SCRIBNER'S MAGAZINE, LI (April, 1912), 1912 Apr. (Box 36, Folder 27)
    - Howe, Frederic C., Garden Cities, SCRIBNER'S MAGAZINE, LII (July, 1912), 1912 July (Box 36, Folder 28)
    - Olmsted, Frederick L., Jr., "The Town-Planning Movement in America," ANNALS OF AMERICAN ACADEMY OF POLITICAL AND SOCIAL SCIENCE, LI (January, 1914), 1914 Jan. (Box 36, Folder 29)
    - DeForest, Robert W., "Housing Movement in America," ANNALS OF AMERICAN ACADEMY OF POLITICAL AND SOCIAL SCIENCE, LI (January, 1914), 1914 Jan. (Box 36, Folder 30)
    - "Shall Our Great Cities Be Made States?" Debate in THE AMERICAN CITY, X (January, February, 1914), 1914 Jan. - 1914 Feb. (Box 36, Folder 31)
    - Howe, Frederic C., THE MODERN CITY AND ITS PROBLEMS; Preface dated December, 1914, 1914 Dec. - 1915 (Box 36, Folder 32)
    - [Anon.], "A New `Model' for City Charters," THE SURVEY, XXXVI (May 27, 1916), 1916 May 27 (Box 36, Folder 33)
    - Hoan, Daniel, Inaugural Address as Mayor of Milwaukee, Apr. 16, 1918, 1918 Apr. 16 (Box 36, Folder 34)
    - Roosevelt, Franklin D., Negative comment on cities, 1919, 1919 Dec. 23 (Box 36, Folder 35)
    - Mumford, Lewis, "The Heritage of the Cities Movement in America: an Historical Survey," JOURNAL OF THE AMERICAN INSTITUTE OF ARCHITECTS, VII (August, 1919), 249-354, 1919 Aug. 7 (Box 36, Folder 36)
    - LITERARY DIGEST reaction to urban figures in Census of 1920 (Box 36, Folder 37)
    - Census of 1920, City reaction to (Box 36, Folder 38)
    - Census of 1920, Data on suburbs (Box 36, Folder 39)
    - George, Walter L., RANDOM IMPRESSIONS OF A CONSERVATIVE ENGLISH RADICAL, 1921 (Box 36, Folder 40)
    - Griffiths, Ernest, "The Urban Auto Problem," NATIONAL MUNICIPAL REVIEW, IX (July, 1920), 1920 July (Box 36, Folder 41)
    - Long, J. C., "Passing of the Hick," Role of automobile, THE OUTLOOK, Nov. 3, 1920, 1920 Nov. 3 (Box 36, Folder 42)
    - Glaab, Charles N., "Metropolis and Suburb: The Changing American City," 1920-1932, in John Braeman, Robert H. Bremner, and David Brody, CHANGE AND CONTINUITY IN TWENTIETH-CENTURY AMERICA (Ohio, 1968) (Box 36, Folder 43)
    - "Town or Country," Pro-urban sentiment, NATION, CXIII (1921), 1921 Oct. 19 (Box 36, Folder 44)
    - Mumford, Lewis, "The Wilderness of Suburbia," NEW REPUBLIC, XXVIII (August-November, 1921), 1921 Aug. - 1921 Nov. (Box 36, Folder 45)
    - Mumford, Lewis, "The City," written for CIVILIZATION IN THE UNITED STATES, ed. by Harold Stearns, 1922 (Box 36, Folder 46)
    - Turner, F. J., References to significance of city, 1922, 1926 (Box 36, Folder 47)
    - Beard, Charles A., "New York, the Metropolis of Today," REVIEW OF REVIEWS, LXIX (June, 1924), 1924 June (Box 36, Folder 48)
    - "The Automobile: Its Province and Its Problems," THE ANNALS, CXVI (November, 1924), 1924 Nov. (Box 36, Folder 49)
    - Florida Real Estate Boom, 1925, 1926 Jan. (Box 36, Folder 50)
    - Douglass, Harlan P., THE SUBURBAN TREND, 1925 (Box 36, Folder 51)
    - Allen, Frederick L., "Suburban Nightmare," THE INDEPENDENT, CXIV -1925 (Box 36, Folder 52)
    - Garrett, Franklin M., ATLANTA AND ENVIRONS (1954), Traffic Change, 1926 (Box 36, Folder 53)
    - Mumford, Lewis, "The Intolerable City...," HARPER'S MAGAZINE, CLII (February, 1926), 1926 Feb. (Box 36, Folder 54)
    - Hoover, Herbert, Services of Federal Government to Cities, 1927, 1927 Nov. (Box 36, Folder 55)
    - Beard, Charles A., "The City's Place in Civilization," THE SURVEY, XLI (Nov. 15, 1928), 1928 Nov. 15 (Box 36, Folder 56)
    - Beard, Charles A., "The City's Place in Civilization," NATIONAL MUNICIPAL REVIEW, XVII (December, 1928), 1928 Dec. (Box 36, Folder 57)
    - Cities in Depression, 1930's (Box 36, Folder 58)
    - Kvasnicka, Robert M., City in Crisis: The Impact of Depression on Detroit, Michigan, 1930's, 1970 (Box 36, Folder 59)
    - Sternsher, Bernard, HITTING HOME: THE GREAT DEPRESSION IN TOWN AND COUNTRY; Published 1970, re 1930's (Box 36, Folder 60)
    - Hallgren, Mauritz A., "Chicago Goes Tammany," NATION, CXXXII (Apr. 22, 1931), 1931 Apr. 22 (Box 36, Folder 61)
    - Bane, Frank, "Feeding the Hungry," NATIONAL MUNICIPAL REVIEW, XXI (November, 1932), 1932 Nov. (Box 36, Folder 62)
    - Merriam, Charles E., "The Federal Government Recognizes the Cities," NATIONAL MUNICIPAL REVIEW, XXIII (February, 1934), 1934 Feb. (Box 36, Folder 63)
    - McKee, Oliver, Jr., "Washington as a Boom Town," NORTH AMERICAN REVIEW, CCXXXIX (February, 1935), 1935 Feb. (Box 36, Folder 64)
    - National Resources Committee. OUR CITIES: THEIR ROLE IN THE NATIONAL ECONOMY, 1937, 1937 June (Box 36, Folder 65)
    - Federal Aid in Depression, THE AMERICAN CITY, LII (January, 1937), 1937 Jan. (Box 37, Folder 1)
      3 1142 04225082 2
    - La Guardia, Fiorello, "Making Democracy Work in the Modern Industrial City," (June, 1939), 1939 June (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Braun, Wallace, "Are Business Streets for Parking or Motoring?" THE AMERICAN CITY, LV (August, 1940), 1940 Aug. (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Schlesinger, A. M., "The City in American History," 1940, 1949 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Wilhelm, Donald, Washington D.C. in Wartime, 1941, 1941 Sept. (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Stein, Clarence, CITY PATTERNS, PAST AND FUTURE, 1942 (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Race Relations, Chicago, Detroit, ca. 1944 (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - Housing Legislation, Hearings, 1945 (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - Optimum City Size, THE AMERICAN CITY, LXVI (August, 1951), 1957 Aug. (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - Saunders, Dero A., "Department Stores: Race for the Suburbs," FORTUNE, XLIV (December, 1951), 1951 Dec. (Box 37, Folder 10)
    - Zeckendorf, Wm., "Cities vs. Suburbs," THE ATLANTIC, CLXXXX (July, 1952), 1952 July (Box 37, Folder 11)
    - Allen, Frederick L., "The Big Change in Suburbia," Part I, HARPER'S MAGAZINE, CCVIII (June, 1954); Part II, HARPER'S MAGAZINE, CCIX (July, 1954) (Box 37, Folder 12)
    - Metropolitan Governments, 1956, 1957, 1970 (Box 37, Folder 13)
    - Daley, Richard, "The Big City's Place in the Metropolitan Area," PROCEEDINGS OF NATIONAL CONFERENCE ON METROPOLITAN PROBLEMS, 1956, 1956 May 2 (Box 37, Folder 14)
    - Freedgood, Seymour, "New Strength in City Hall," Reprint from FORTUNE Magazine, November, 1957, 1957 Nov. (Box 37, Folder 15)
    - Bello, Francis, "The City and the Car," in THE EXPLODING METROPOLIS, 1958 (Box 37, Folder 16)
    - Briggs, Asa, "The Study of Cities," CONFLUENCE, VII (1958) (Box 37, Folder 17)
    - Hauser, Philip, "Impact of Urbanism on Social Organization, Human Nature, and the Political Order," CONFLUENCE, VII (1958) (Box 37, Folder 18)
    - Wilson, Everett K., "Some Notes on the Pains and Prospects of American Cities," CONFLUENCE, VII (1958) (Box 37, Folder 19)
    - Kennedy, John F., "The Shame of the States," NEW YORK TIMES MAGAZINE, May 18, 1958, 1958 May 18 (Box 37, Folder 20)
    - Geen, Elizabeth, ET AL, eds. MAN AND THE MODERN CITY, 1959-60; published 1963, 1959-1960 (Box 37, Folder 21)
    - Whyte, Wm. H., "The Anti-City," in Geen, MAN AND THE MODERN CITY, 1959-60; published, 1963 (Box 37, Folder 22)
    - Miami Metro, 1959-64, 1959-1964 (Box 37, Folder 23)
    - Election of 1960 Suburban Vote, 1961 Apr. 9 (Box 37, Folder 24)
    - Kennedy, John F., Cities, Quotations on, 1960-1962; published 1965 (Box 37, Folder 25)
    - Housing, 1960-1968 (Box 37, Folder 26)
    - "New Towns," 1960's, 1970's (Box 37, Folder 27)
    - Gottman, Jean, MEGALOPOLIS, 1961 (Box 37, Folder 28)
    - Atkinson, Brooks, City vs. Country, NEW YORK TIMES, 1961, 1962, 1961 Jan. 17, 1962 Oct. 26 (Box 37, Folder 29)
    - Kennedy, J. F. and Department of Housing and Urban Affairs, 1961, ff. (Box 37, Folder 30)
    - Harrington, Michael, THE OTHER AMERICA, 1962 (Box 37, Folder 31)
    - Reed, Thomas H., Metropolitan Government, NATIONAL CIVIC REVIEW, LI (March, 1962), 1962 March (Box 37, Folder 32)
    - Havemann, Ernest, "Rebirth of Philadelphia," NATIONAL CIVIC REVIEW, LI (March, 1962), 1962 March (Box 37, Folder 33)
    - Stouffer, Lloyd, "Breaking Traffic Jam," NATIONAL CIVIC REVIEW, LI (October, 1962), 1962 Oct. (Box 37, Folder 34)
    - Jacobs, Jane, 1963, 1969 (Box 37, Folder 35)
    - THE HARVARD REVIEW (Fall, 1964), Issue devoted to the American City: Edward C. Banfield, Daniel Bell, Edgar and Jean Kahn, Paul Goodman, Bayard Rustin, Robert C. Weaver (Box 37, Folder 36)
    - Moses, Robert, Biography to 1965 (Box 37, Folder 37)
    - Cunningham, James V., THE RESURGENT NEIGHBORHOOD, 1965 (Box 37, Folder 38)
    - Vernon, Raymond, MYTH AND REALITY OF OUR URBAN PROBLEMS, 1965 (Box 37, Folder 39)
    - Elazar, Daniel J., "Are We a Nation of Cities?" PUBLIC INTEREST (Summer, 1966) (Box 37, Folder 40)
    - Living Preference, Poll on, PHILADELPHIA BULLETIN, Mar. 20, 1966, 1966 Mar. 20 (Box 37, Folder 41)
    - Weaver, Robert C., THE URBAN COMPLEX, 1966 (Box 37, Folder 42)
    - Gutheim, Frederick, "The Institutional Setting of Urban Affairs," URBAN AMERICA: GOALS AND PROBLEMS, 1967 (Box 37, Folder 43)
    - Curtis, Thomas B., "Power and Urban Growth," URBAN AMERICA: GOALS AND PROBLEMS, 1967 (Box 37, Folder 44)
    - Elazar, Daniel J., "Urbanization and Federalism in the United States," URBAN AMERICA: GOALS AND PROBLEMS, 1967 (Box 37, Folder 45)
    - Clark, Sen. Joseph S., "The New Urbanism," GOALS FOR URBAN AMERICA, 1967 (Box 37, Folder 46)
    - Toward a Coherent National Urban Policy, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 47)
    - Daley, Richard, Chicago Machine, 1967, 1968, 1967 Mar. 13, 1968 Feb. 12 (Box 37, Folder 48)
    - Berger, Bennett M., WORKING-CLASS SUBURB, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 49)
    - Gavin, J. M. and Arthur Hadley, "The Crisis of the Cities," SATURDAY REVIEW, Feb. 24, 1968, 1968 Feb. 24 (Box 37, Folder 50)
    - Halberstam, David, "Daley of Chicago," HARPER'S MAGAZINE, CCXXXVII (August, 1968), 1968 Aug. (Box 37, Folder 51)
    - Rockefeller, David, address, "Social Responsibilities of Business to Urban America," Oct. 26, 1968, 1968 Oct. 26 (Box 37, Folder 52)
    - "Great Society," NEW YORK TIMES, Dec. 10, 1968, 1968 Dec. 10 (Box 37, Folder 53)
    - Moynihan, Daniel P., "Toward a National Urban Policy," THE PUBLIC INTEREST (Fall, 1969) (Box 37, Folder 54)
    - Miller, Kenneth H., "Community Organizations in the Ghetto," 1969 (Box 37, Folder 55)
    - Blacks and Jews, TIME, Jan. 31, 1969, 1969 Jan. 31 (Box 37, Folder 56)
    - Articles on New York in THE PUBLIC INTEREST (Summer, 1969) -- Mayoralty, Ethnic, Black, Liberals (Box 37, Folder 57)
    - Attitudes toward New York of Brooks Atkinson, Saul Bellow, S. J. Perelman (1970) (Box 37, Folder 58)
    - Attitudes toward New York and City (Miscellaneous) (1972) (Box 37, Folder 59)
    - Archdeacon, Thomas J., "Chapter VI: Ethnic Politics," from The Age of Leisler: New York City, 16891710: A Social and Demographic Interpretation, Columbia University doctoral dissertation, 1971 (Box 65, Folder 12)
    - Mohl, Raymond A., "An Ethnic 'Boiling Pot': Cubans and Haitians in Miami," THE JOURNAL OF ETHNIC STUDIES vol. 13 no. 2, 1985 Summer (Box 65, Folder 13)
    - Roby, Pamela, Politics and Prostitution: A Case Study of the Formulation, Enforcement, and Judicial Administration of the New York State Penal Laws on Prostitution, 1870-1970, doctoral dissertation, undated (Box 65, Folder 14)
  - Subseries D: Mirror For Gotham Research Materials
    - Photographs -- Street Scenes, undated (Box 73, Folder 1)
    - Photographs -- Prominent Buildings, Structures, and Bridges, undated (Box 73, Folder 2)
    - Photographs -- People, undated (Box 73, Folder 3)
    - Photographs -- Engravings and Drawings, Old New York (Pre-19th Century), Buildings, and People, undated (Box 73, Folder 4)
    - Photographs -- Views of New York (Panoramas), 1942 (Box 73, Folder 5)
    - Photographs -- New York Scenes from the Late 19th Century to Early 20th Century, undated (Box 73, Folder 6)
    - Notes and Clippings, 1972 (Box 73, Folder 7)
    - Photographs -- Historic Houses in NY, undated (Box Shared University Archives 152, Folder 2)
    - Photographs from Professor Still's Office, 1985 (Box Shared University Archives 152, Folder 3-4)
- Series IV: Speeches, Reviews, Doctoral Student Files, Mayoral Research, NYU Archives, 1947-1976
  Series IV contains speeches, materials related to reviews of other historians' works written by Still, Still's files on his doctoral students, research files on the New York City Office of the Mayor, and materials documenting Still's work with the University Archives.
  - Subseries A: Speeches, Reviews, Press
    Subseries A: Speeches, Reviews, Press consists of speeches that Still gave before various historical organizations. Also in this subseries are publications, correspondence, and information regarding Still's professional associations.
    - Speech, Class Night, Heights, Jun. 5, 1961, 1967 Jun. 5 (Box 38, Folder 1)
      3 1142 04225083 0
    - Speech, Class Night, Heights, Jun. 7, 1965, 1965 Jun. 7 (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Speech, Perstare et Praestare, Feb. 18, 1965, 1965 Feb. 18 (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - "The American City in History and Literature," Intercollegiate Conference on Urban Affairs, Long Island University, Mar. 8-10, 1963, 1963 Mar. 8-10 (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Speech, Long Island University, Dec. 13, 1962: "The History of the City in American Life", 1962 Dec. 13 (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - THE WEST, Letters from readers; reference to French edition, 1961, 1962, 1965 (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - Wisconsin Biographical Project, 1950 Aug. 11 (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - "New York City" ms. for WORLD SCOPE ENCYCLOPEDIA, 1957 (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - Olmsted, Frederick L., Account of Chicago Fire, NATION, Nov. 9, 1871, 1871 Nov. 9 (Box 38, Folder 9)